<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<whats_on_feed>
    <programs>
<program>
    <id>545212:start_date_ts=1340332200,end_date_ts=1340332200,type_code=calendar_event_multi_date</id>
    <category><![CDATA[NGV Talks]]></category>
    <subcategory><![CDATA[]]></subcategory>
    <type>single</type>
    <name>Date 2325</name>
    <title><![CDATA[Floor Talk: Gerard Vaughan on the Salon Room and Regency Room]]></title>
    <exhibition><![CDATA[NGV International Collection]]></exhibition>
    <exhibition_id><![CDATA[3518]]></exhibition_id>
    <start_time><![CDATA[12:30]]></start_time>
    <end_time><![CDATA[:]]></end_time>
    <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
    <venue><![CDATA[Information Desk]]></venue>
    <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
    <level><![CDATA[Level G]]></level>
    <ticketing_info><![CDATA[]]></ticketing_info>
    <booking_code><![CDATA[]]></booking_code>
    <description><![CDATA[<P>Join our esteemed Director as he speaks on favourite works on display in the nineteenth century painting and sculpture galleries.</P>]]></description>
</program>        </programs>
        <tours>    </tours>
    <exhibitions>
        <exhibition>
            <id>519935</id>
            <title><![CDATA[Napoleon]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[Revolution to Empire]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[02 Jun 2012]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[07 Oct 2012]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Ticketed]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[<strong>Open 10am-5pm daily, until 9pm Wednesdays</strong><br />
<br />
<em>Napoleon: Revolution to Empire</em> is a panoramic exhibition examining French art, culture and life from the 1770s to the 1820s. Its story runs from the first French voyages of discovery to Australia during the reign of Louis XV to the end of Napoleon’s transforming leadership as first Emperor of France. Book now at <a href="http://www.ticketmaster.com.au/napoleon/">http://www.ticketmaster.com.au/napoleon</a>]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level G]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[Temporary Exhibition Space 1, 2 & 3]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images>
<img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0015/553200/Napoleon04_info.jpg" width="768" height="1365" />
<img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0004/553198/Napoleon05_info.jpg" width="768" height="1365" />
<img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0010/553195/Napoleon09_info.jpg" width="768" height="1365" />
<img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0011/553196/Napoleon14_info.jpg" width="768" height="1365" />
</images>          
</exhibition>
        <exhibition>
            <id>105793</id>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dr Robert Wilson Collection]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[of 19th Century Ceramics and Glass]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[03 Dec 2010]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[01 Oct 2012]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Dr Robert Wilson is one of the most significant benefactors to the Decorative Arts Department of the National Gallery of Victoria. For many years he has been steadily gifting works from his remarkable collection of 19th century ceramics and glass, including Minton, Worcester, Copeland, Burmantofts, Doulton and Thomas Webb. His passion for Minton, pursued with a singular intensity, might even be said to border on an obsession. Yet if this is the case, it is an obsession with the best aims in mind. He has always selected the best. There are no compromises in this collection; everything is of superb quality and much is highly important for its rarity.]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level 2]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[Balcony & Decorative Arts Passage]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images />          </exhibition>
        <exhibition>
            <id>116919</id>
            <title><![CDATA[Art of the Pacific]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[28 May 2011]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[31 Dec 2012]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[The National Gallery of Victoria believes that it is vital to honour the art and culture of the Pacific so that it will be perceived here in Melbourne as one of the world’s great art traditions that continues to develop and is open to change. To that end the NGV opened its first Oceanic gallery at NGV International in December 2003. The Oceanic gallery enabled the NGV to create a Pacific presence on the ground floor but the scale of the permanent gallery did not do justice to the importance of Pacific Islander art or to the NGV’s vision for the Asia Pacific region that embraces Indigenous Australia, the Pacific and Asia. On 28 May 2011, synchronous with the NGV’s 150th anniversary, the Gallery opened to the public a modern permanent space dedicated to art of the Pacific with a special focus on the work of living artists. In this dynamic white cube, art of the Pacific moves out of its darkened cul-de-sac and into a light-filled 21st century space with a 5 metre ceiling.<br>]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level 3]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[Art of the Pacific]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images />          </exhibition>
        <exhibition>
            <id>529780</id>
            <title><![CDATA[Light Works]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2012]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[16 Sep 2012]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[The sun’s light is an elemental force of nature without which our planet would not exist. Light is also fundamental for the creation of photographs, indeed some of the first photographs were named ‘calotype’ meaning a ‘beautiful impression’ created by light. Light, and its absence, it still a source of inspiration for many contemporary photographers. In this exhibition drawn from the NGV Collection, artists including Mike and Doug Starn, David Stephenson, Hiroshi Sugimoto and Bill Henson, use the emotive potential and scientific capacities of light in their creative explorations of the world. Works included range from photograms (camera-less images); large scale installations and digital light-based technologies.&nbsp;]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level 3]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[Photography]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images />          </exhibition>
        <exhibition>
            <id>539965</id>
            <title><![CDATA[An Excellent Adventure]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[31 Mar 2012]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[03 Feb 2013]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[<p><i>An Excellent Adventure</i> invites children on a journey inspired by a time when sailing ships explored the seven seas. Climb aboard with our two intrepid young adventurers and along the way discover treasures, stories, myths and legends. Peek into the wonderful cabinets of curiosities to examine the intricacies of the ushabti figures from Egypt, ancient stories recorded on artworks from the Mediterranean and Asian symbols found throughout the NGV collection. Through hands on and multimedia experiences, children aged 0 - 8 and their families can journey together to explore the world through art. Excellent!</p>]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level G]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[NGV Kids Space]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images>
<img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0009/545679/EA_info_mascot.jpg" width="768" height="790" />
</images>          </exhibition>
        <exhibition>
            <id>529784</id>
            <title><![CDATA[Brent Harris]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[10 Mar 2012]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[12 Aug 2012]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[Brent Harris is one of Australia’s leading contemporary artists.&nbsp; A prolific painter and printmaker, he is well known for haunting imagery that drifts between abstraction and figuration. Charged with a quiet emotional intensity, his paintings, prints and drawings are often motivated by an exploration of personal memories and the expression of psychological states. Sometimes humorous and often disturbing, they address a range of universal concerns relating to human experience:&nbsp;life, death, fear, doubt, spirituality and sexuality. Encompassing more than&nbsp;70 works drawn predominantly from the NGV Collection, this exhibition looks at the development of Harris’s unique vision over a career of more than twenty years, exploring the ways that he has continually transformed his approach to image-making from his earliest prints and drawings to his most recent paintings.<BR>]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level 3]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[Robert Raynor Gallery Prints & Drawings]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images />          </exhibition>
        <exhibition>
            <id>539096</id>
            <title><![CDATA[UNEXPECTED PLEASURES]]></title>
            <subtitle><![CDATA[The Art and Design of Contemporary Jewellery]]></subtitle>
            <opening_date><![CDATA[20 Apr 2012]]></opening_date>
            <closing_date><![CDATA[26 Aug 2012]]></closing_date>
            <entry><![CDATA[Free]]></entry>
            <short_description><![CDATA[<p>
<b>A Design Museum, London touring exhibition</b><br><br><em>Unexpected Pleasures</em> looks at what we mean by jewellery from a number of different perspectives.&nbsp; Taking as its starting point the radical experiments of the Contemporary Jewellery Movement that challenged a conventional understanding of the language of personal adornment, and looking instead at the essential meanings of jewellery, the exhibition brings together important work from around the world, and looks at it from the point of view of the wearer as well as the maker.&nbsp;Contemporary&nbsp; Jewellery in this sense is at the intersection of art and design.<br></p><p>Curated by Dr. Susan Cohn for the Design Museum, London with exhibition design by Ab Rogers Design and graphics by Barnbrook.
</p>]]></short_description>
            <location><![CDATA[NGVI]]></location>
            <level><![CDATA[Level G]]></level>
            <venue><![CDATA[Contemporary Exhibitions]]></venue>
            <highlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></highlight_colour>
            <lowlight_colour><![CDATA[]]></lowlight_colour>
        <images>
<img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0003/548427/UnexpectedPleasures_info01.jpg" width="768" height="790" /><img src="http://www.ngv.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/image/0004/548428/UnexpectedPleasures_info02.jpg" width="768" height="790" />
</images>          </exhibition>

    </exhibitions>
</whats_on_feed>